Babe.
宝贝 来
Let me help you.
妈妈帮你
Hope the food suits your taste.
不知道你们集训的地方
In case it's cold there,
伙食怎么样 冷不冷
better pack those
还是把这些毛衣啊
sweaters and jackets.
外套都带上吧
Mom, no worries.
妈 不用
It's not cold.
现在不冷
It will, at night.
晚上冷
It's all
有一种冷
in your head.
叫你妈觉得你冷
Of course I'm worried!
妈妈能不操心吗
It's your first big trip after all.
宝贝 你第一次出远门
How about
要不这样吧
having your dad
还是让你爸爸
dropping you off tomorrow?
明天送你去
C'mon, mom.
妈 不用了
It's just a month
我集训就一个月
and I'm all grown up.
而且我这么大的人了
Nothing to worry about.
有什么不放心的
Oh, no.
不对 不对 不对
Gotta pack your long johns.
我得给你带上秋裤
Mom!
妈
You...
你 你
What are you doing?
干嘛呢
Whoops, get caught.
糟糕 被发现了
Sleepwalking?
梦游吗
He's doubting me?
你不会怀疑我吧
So scary.
大半夜怪吓人的
Whatever.
怀疑就怀疑
I'll find it sooner or later.
反正我早晚能找出来
You're not here to hang with me,
你回来不像是陪我玩啊
but to mess with me instead.
倒像是在玩我
Since it's not in the study,
既然书房找不到
the next target is...
那下一个目标就是
To hit the bed.
先睡为敬
What?
什么
I sleepwalked again last night?
我昨天晚上又梦游了
You sure you're sleepwalking?
你确定是在梦游
Or were you just messing with me?
不是在整我
Granny.
外婆
Whenever I sleep
我每次到一个
in a room that has been
很久都没有人
idle for long,
住过的房间睡觉
I always end up sleepwalking.
我都会梦游
Right, that guest room
对了 那个客房啊
hasn't been used in ages.
好久是没人住了
Gosh.
妈呀
You're giving me the chills.
你说的吓死人了真是
Thankfully,
小妹啊
you didn't wander off outside,
你亏的是在家里边梦游
that could've been
你这要是梦游到外边去
really dangerous.
那得多危险
So what now?
那怎么办啊
What if I
我今天晚上
sleepwalk outside tonight?
不会又梦游到外面去吧
That'd be nice.
那不是正好啊
Don't worry.
别害怕
Li'l Su.
小妹啊
Skip the guest room tonight
今天哪 你别睡客房了
and bunk with me.
跟外婆一起睡了
Yeah.
对对对
Sleep with Granny,
跟外婆睡在一块儿
she'll keep an eye on you.
让外婆晚上好好看着你
But...
可是
But what?
可是什么呀
I did a sleep test overseas.
我在国外做过睡眠监测
The report said that I've got
医生说我有很严重的
severe sleep restlessness.
睡眠多动症
It's like I get all wiggly
就是我睡着的时候啊
and punchy
手和脚都不受
when I'm
自己的控制
asleep,
会打人的
so I gotta sleep solo.
所以我只能一个人睡
That bad?
还那么严重哪
What now?
那怎么办
The other rooms
那其他的客房
haven't been used
也都是好久
in a while too.
都没有人睡过了
Can't put you in the living room, huh?
总不能让你睡客厅吧
I have a proposal,
我有一个提议
not sure if Jinghui will go for it.
不知道表哥会不会同意
No.
不同意
Well.
就是
Mind if I crash in
你能不能把你的房间
your room tonight?
让给我睡啊
No way!
不可能
I'm a teen boy
我一个青春期的男孩
with secrets,
我有很多小的秘密的
My room's
而且我不可能
not an option.
把房间让给你
And I just
而且我不是刚刚说过
said no.
我不同意吗
Uncle.
舅舅 行行行
I guess I'll have to
那看来今晚
sleep in the couch then.
我只能睡客厅了
You're not.
不可能让你睡客厅啊
Jinghui.
小灰
She's a young lady
你妹妹她是一个小姑娘
and a guest too.
又是咱们家的客人
No way she's sleeping on the couch.
能让她睡客厅吗
Swap rooms with her,
把你房间腾出来
alright?
你俩换房间
Dad!
爸 你
Granny, help me.
奶奶 你帮我说说
Jinghui.
小灰啊
Be a good host.
你表妹来咱家不容易
Just do it.
你就让让她吧
Granny.
奶奶
Even you're not backing me up?
怎么连你也不帮着我啊
I am.
我这帮你啊
I'll clean up that
我一会儿把那客房啊
guest room for you.
给你再整理一下
What?
不是 奶奶
What kind of backup is that?
这算哪门子帮啊
Thanks. Granny.
谢谢外婆
Jinghui.
表哥
You're the best!
我就知道你最好了
No! I'm not!
我不好
I'm all messed up now.
我整个人都不好了
Eat up.
多吃点 多吃点
Yeah.
吃吃吃
Excuse me.
让让 让让
Don't touch around!
不能乱碰我的东西
I know.
知道 知道
First,
第一
don't touch my Legos.
不能碰我的乐高
I'm not that interested.
我还不稀
Second,
第二
don't touch my bed.
不能碰我的床
What's your problem?
你有病啊
I need a bed to sleep!
床不碰我怎么睡
I...
我
Alright, you can use the bed.
行 那床可以碰啊
But that thing,
但唯独这个
not even a touch.
碰都不能碰一下
You got it?
记住没有
Yeah.
知道了
Out of my room.
你赶快离开我的房间
Go, go.
走走走
Keep that in mind.
记得我的叮嘱
Yes, yes.
知道 知道
Go.
走走走
Bro.
兄弟
I miss you a lot.
我想死你了
Perfect timing.
你来的太是时候了
What happened?
你这是怎么了
Granny.
奶奶好
Oh, it's Ling Dong.
他二表舅来了
You haven't eaten yet?
还没吃饭吧
Not yet.
没呢
I'll whip up something for you.
我去给你做饭去
Nah, too much hassle.
会不会太麻烦你了
Don't worry about it.
这有什么麻烦的
It's no biggie.
没事
We're a family.
来来来 客里客气的
Here.
来来来
Slippers.
换鞋 换鞋 换鞋
Come.
快快快
Have a seat.
坐坐坐
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
Can I borrow your telescope?
找你借望远镜啊
You do have one, right?
你家不是有吗
Telescope? For what?
不是 借望远镜干嘛呢
To look at stars.
追星
According to astronomical forecasts,
根据天文预报显示
a super rare thing's happening
今天晚上到二十二号
This.
就这个
in the sky tonight till the 22nd.
将会有一次非常罕见的
Jupiter and Saturn are gonna
木星与土星相合天象
line up real close.
亮相天宇
From the Earth...
从地球上看过去
Sure, you can use the telescope,
望远镜借给你没有问题
but with one condition.
但我有一个条件
Take me with you.
带上我一块去
Seriously?
不会吧
You're into this?
你对这件事感兴趣
Special circumstances.
今时不同与往日
I gotta get rid of
我现在务必要
a little monkey.
甩掉一个冤家
Who do you mean?
你说谁是冤家
I think
这位哥哥
I've met you before.
好像在哪里见过
Hands off.
禁止肌肤接触
Go away.
去去去
This is?
这位是
She...
这位
- is the little monkey... - Hi, I'm Su Xi.
这位是冤家 我叫苏夕
Lan Jinghui is my cousin.
兰靖灰是我表哥
What's your name, boy?
漂亮哥哥你叫什么呀
I'm...
我
Ling Dong.
我叫凌冬
Jinghui.
哥
In person,
见了真人
I can confidently tell you that
我负责任地告诉你
he's quite the looker.
他比你帅
Think before you speak.
谨言慎行啊 怎么说话
Alright.
行
Where's your telescope?
你那个望远镜在哪儿呢
I'll grab it.
我去拿
Come on, I know
我带你去啊
where it is.
我知道
Where's your telescope?
望远镜在哪
She knows nothing.
知道什么她知道
How about this.
要不这样吧
We're going stargazing together,
你不是要跟我一起去嘛
so just bring it
到时候你
with you then.
你拿着就行了
I'll see myself out.
我先走了
I'll come with you.
我送送你 走吧
Where are you guys going?
你们要去哪儿
Count me in.
我也要去
None of your business.
小孩管那么多干什么
Just stay at home.
搁家待着
Really?
真的
Going for JU,
真考京大
no RU?
不考蓉大了
Yes.
决定了
Finally come around.
终于想通了
Mom's the one
要我说啊
who knows how to
这就是解铃还须系铃人
fix things, huh?
这还是阿姨厉害啊
To be honest,
不过其实
still got a lot of problems to tackle.
还是有很多问题的
What?
不是
Since your mom's agreed
既然阿姨都已经答应
to go with you,
跟你一块去了
no more
那你还有什么
to worry about.
放心不下的
Don't be
要我说就是
a worrier.
你这心思太重了
Just focus on your goal,
有目标冲就完事了
right?
不是吗
But if,
但是万一
I mean...
万一啊
if I somehow
我说万一如果是我
get in JU
真的考上京大了
but you don't,
你没报
it's like, my flurry of wild punches
那我是不是就成了
defeat a master like you.
乱拳打死老师傅
Well.
不是
You feelin' pretty confident, eh?
你对自己就这么有信心
Yep.
那可不
I, Lan Jinghui,
我兰靖灰认定的事情
will definitely make it.
一定会做到
Okay.
行
But I think
不过我劝你
now you should focus on
现在还是好好考虑一下
handling
怎么解决
your cousin.
你那个冤家表妹吧
Hey, listen up.
过来我跟你说个事
I noticed
我就发现
she's been
这个苏小妹她吧
snooping around
平时在我这个房间里边
in my room.
真的是
Really.
到处翻找
What's up with you and that girl?
你和那姑娘怎么样了
She's
她呀
at my games every day,
每天都来看我打球
don't you see?
你们没发现吗
I'm over it already.
我都快腻了
Her mom's
她妈是不是
that writer, right?
那个有名的作家
And she's my teacher too.
是啊 还是我老师呢
Think the girl's gonna
你们说这姑娘
show up
今天会不会
to your game today?
来看茂哥打球呀
I bet she won't.
我赌不会
I bet she will.
我赌会
No doubt about it.
这还用说嘛
One text from me,
只要我给消息
and she's there.
她绝对会来
Stop bragging.
你别吹牛了
I'm not.
我可没吹牛啊
She doesn't come,
到时候来不了
you'll be looking silly.
看你尴不尴尬
Alright.
好了 好了
Enough about this.
不说了 不说了
Let's make a deal,
今天说好了啊
loser buys dinner.
谁输了谁请客啊
You've always been my easy win.
你哪次不是我手下败将
Ma'am, I'm done.
老师 我画好了
Finished.
老师
Bye.
再见
Ma'am, I'm done.
老师 我也好了
- I'm done. - Me too.
我画好了 我也画好了
Bye.
老师再见
Mengyu.
梦予
Thought you'd be
我以为你学习紧张
too busy studying.
不会来了
Nah.
没有
Needed a break.
正好过来放松一下
After this game,
那你等我打完这场
let's grab something tasty.
我就带你去吃好吃的
Okay.
好
Yeah. Be right back.
好 等我一下
Come.
走
Ma Yiming, what's wrong with you?
马一鸣 你干什么
Keep your distance from that guy,
你能不能离那个人
okay?
远点啊
Who?
什么
Ma Mao.
马茂
You know
你知不知道
he's bad news, right?
他不是个好东西
You think you know him?
马一鸣 你跟他很熟吗
We've known
他是我师哥
each other for ages.
我们认识很多年了
I know him
他好不好
better than you.
我比你更清楚
I'm serious,
我跟你说真的呢
don't want you to get hurt.
我不想让你受伤
Mind your own
我跟谁走得近
business.
跟你没有任何关系
Who do you
你是谁啊
think you are?
你凭什么管我
Hello everyone.
各位观众 大家好
According to the forecast,
根据天文预报显示
there'll be a very rare
二十二号将会有一次
astronomical event
非常罕见的
of Jupiter and Saturn conjunction
木星和土星相合天象
on the 22nd.
届时
The angular distance between them
木星与土星的角距离
will reach 6.19 minutes arc.
将会达到六点一九分
From the perspective of the earth,
从地球上看过去
Jupiter and Saturn
木星与土星的距离
will be extremely close.
将会极为接近
Experts said that
专家称我国境内
the best time to observe
最佳观测这次天象的
in China is one hour after dark
时间是二十一号傍晚
on the evening of the 21st.
天黑后的一个小时
Why are you dressed
你怎么打扮得
like a star?
跟个明星似的
Not really.
谈不上明星吧
Used to be Captain Chenjun.
曾经的辰郡之光罢了
Why'd you
那你把我叫过来
drag me here?
是要干嘛呀
I had to sneak out
我是好不容易
by pretending
找了个买书的借口
to buy books.
才溜出来的
You have no idea,
你都不知道
my cousin's eyes
苏小妹的眼睛
are on me
就像装了定位器一样
like a hawk.
一刻都不松懈
Perhaps it's just
你觉得有没有可能
a misunderstanding.
是你误会人家了
No way.
不可能
Got any proof that
那你又有什么证据
she's up to something?
能证明她有鬼呢
This is the proof.
这就是证据
It's
这
a pencil lead?
是根笔芯
Of course.
当然
Are you serious?
你是不是傻
Sorry, I broke it.
不好意思 把你弄断了
But this is so silly.
但是你这也太傻了吧
Bring it to the bookstore?
带根笔芯来书店
But that thing over there,
但唯独这个
not even a touch.
碰都不能碰一下
You got it?
记住没有
Yeah.
知道了
Out of my room.
你赶快离开我的房间
Go, go.
走走
Where is it...
在哪儿啊
I'm heading down to grab a bite.
我要下楼去吃点东西了
Don't touch it.
你别动这里呀
You hear me?
别动你听到没
You said your cousin
你不是说
lives abroad all year round,
你那个表妹常年在国外
and you haven't seen her in years,
好几年都没见过了吗
so what could she possibly be up to?
她能有什么企图啊
Yeah.
对啊
It's the creepy part.
这才是最可怕的不是吗
You know
你明明知道
something's
这个人不对劲
not right with her,
但你又说不出来
but you can't say what.
她哪里不对劲
This whole situation
你不觉得
gives me the heebie-jeebies.
想想就不对劲吗这件事
But
可是
there's nothing I can do.
这我也帮不上什么忙呀
Please.
别呀
She likes chatting
我表妹不是很乐意
with you,
跟你聊天吗
so just keep her talking
那你就跟她聊啊
and see if you can
你就趁她不备的时候
find out what she's up to.
探探她的底细
I won't do it.
我不去
You gotta help me out with this, bro.
这个忙你一定得帮兄弟
What's in it for me?
那我能有什么好处啊
My dear uncle.
二表舅
My desk mate.
好同桌
My good bro.
好兄弟
If you help me with this,
如果你帮了我这个忙
I'll finish every exercise
三年高考 五年模拟
whatever it takes.
我吃我也给它吃完
Stop.
打住
No way, even if you
你今天就算是叫我爸爸
call me Dad.
我也不答应
Grandpa.
爷爷
What was that?
有点没听清
Don't push your luck.
差不多得了
Alright,
你看 你看
come back.
坐坐坐
You mad?
生气了
Already?
你这就生气了
I'll do it, okay?
我答应你还不行嘛
I'll give it a try,
我去试试
all right?
我去试试 行不行
Huh?
可不可以
Say something.
说句话呀 说句话
I said yes.
我都答应你了
Look at you.
你看你
Take it off.
别 别戴上
Pretty handsome.
这样挺帅的
Right?
你看是不是
Say something.
说句话 说句话 说句话
I said I'll do it.
我都答应你了
Handsome?
帅吗
Yeah.
确实
Charming.
帅帅帅
Like, ever.
第一无敌 帅
Ling Dong.
凌冬哥哥
Here.
来了
I got you their
我帮你点好了
famous bubble tea.
这是他家店的招牌
Thanks.
谢谢凌冬哥哥
How is it?
怎么样
Yummy!
好喝
You return to China annually?
你是每年都会回国玩吗
Not really.
没有啊
I love hitting the road.
我特别喜欢到处去玩
Just got back from Atacama.
我刚去了阿塔卡马
I know Atacama
阿塔卡马我知道
has incredibly clear skies
夜空晴朗率非常高
and it's recognized worldwide
而且是全球公认的
as the best place for stargazing.
观星最佳地点
I'd love to go there someday.
我有机会也想去
Let's do Atacama next.
那下次我们一起去啊
I got you covered.
我熟 我给你当导游
Yeah, sure.
行 那有机会
The little monkey's
小丫头片子
two-faced.
还两副面孔
Don't trip on her tricks.
别被她迷惑
Let us do Atacama next.
以后我们一起去
Ling Dong.
凌冬哥哥
You're smart,
你成绩又好
and good-looking,
长得又好
perfect in every way.
哪儿哪儿都好
How'd you end up
怎么会和我表哥
being buds with my cousin?
这样的人做朋友
Your cousin's
你表哥这个人呀
got a few issues.
确实毛病多
Moody,
脾气差
bad grades,
成绩又不好
doesn't play by the rules,
做事不讲规矩
and can be rude.
还不讲礼貌
Plus, he can be
而且有时候吧
a bit goofy.
还憨憨的
Yeah. Goofy.
对 憨憨的
Besides me,
所以除了我
hardly anyone's his friend.
几乎没人跟他做朋友
As his only buddy,
那你作为他唯一的朋友
you must know him very well.
你是不是很了解他
I'd say I know him inside out.
那可以说是了如指掌
Let me ask you.
那我考考你
Where does he hide
他最重要的东西
his goodies?
都放在哪儿
Goodies?
最重要的东西啊
You mean?
是什么
Like
就
his ID, bank cards?
证件啊 银行卡什么的
- Ah, those... - You know?
你说这个 你知道
I don't.
我不知道
Why are you asking about this?
你为什么问这个啊
Just...
还不 是
trying to
还不是为了
get to know him better.
多了解一下他
This is so delicious,
这个奶茶真好喝
I'm gonna grab another one
我要再买一杯
to take home for my grandma.
带回去给我外婆
Almost spilled the beans.
差点说漏嘴
Two
帮我来两杯
bubble teas, please.
你们家的招牌奶茶
Alright, coming up.
好的 稍等
Must be distracted by his looks.
帅哥误事 帅哥误事
Your cousin's weird,
你表妹确实有点古怪
she asked about your IDs
她好像很关心你的证件
and bank cards.
还有银行卡在哪儿
Oh, no.
完了
She's got all my passwords,
我的密码她都知道
she's clearly in it for the dough.
奔着钱来的
She's your cousin, come on.
那是你表妹 想什么呢
What's the plan?
那接下来怎么办
Keep an eye on her.
盯住她
Well.
别说
This facial mask's pretty good.
这面膜还挺好用的
You scared me.
吓我一跳
Of course.
那可不
It's pretty pricey.
这面膜可不便宜
Why're you using
你大白天的
my mask during the day?
敷我面膜干吗
You're using one too.
你不也在敷吗
Seeing this guy
我一看这人
reminds me of a movie
我想起我之前看一电影
where the thief tried to steal
电影里面那个小偷
from the lead guy
也要偷男主的东西
by searching
小偷居然去
his bedroom
男主的家里的卧室
and study.
和书房去翻
Like, who keeps
你说哪有人
their valuables
会把那么重要东西
in the bedroom or study?
放到卧室和书房对不对
Not the study? Then where?
那不放书房放哪儿
A safe?
保险柜吗
No way.
怎么可能
That's like
你放在保险柜
telling the thief,
那就等于告诉小偷
"Come and get it!"
三个字 快来拿
Where would you put them?
那要是你你会放哪儿
I'd...
我的话
Where?
哪里
I ain't got nothing
我又没有什么
worth stealing.
值钱的东西
My sneakers are the most
我最值钱的肯定就是
expensive thing I got,
我那些球鞋什么的
but they're
但球鞋
so smelly,
那么臭
who'd want them?
谁会偷你鞋 对不对
You gotta be more careful.
你这人就没有安全意识
You can't just
很多东西
leave them lying around,
都是不能乱放的
like wallets, ID card,
比如钱包啊 身份证啊
band cards,
银行卡啊
and... passports.
护 护照什么的
Replacing them is
这些东西丢了
a nightmare.
都很麻烦的
My valuables are all
那么重要的东西
securely tucked away
我肯定是放在
in the storage room.
储藏室里面
Safe and sound.
保管得很妥当啊
I've been tired lately.
最近可能是有点太累了
My skin's dry.
皮肤真的有点干
I'm gonna wash up.
行 我先去洗了啊
Enjoy your TV.
你接着看吧
Huidora's box?
灰多拉盒子
Why's he storing
桌子里面
smelly socks in the drawer?
放这么多臭袜子干什么
He's hiding something?
难道是障眼法
So stinky!
太臭了
I've heard of Pandora's Box,
潘多拉盒子听过
but what's this Huidora's box?
灰多拉盒子什么东西
It's locked.
还有锁
It should be inside.
应该就在这儿
Where's the key?
钥匙呢
Why does he have so many keys?
怎么会有这么多钥匙
Whatcha searching for?
找什么呢
Passport.
护照啊
Hi, Jinghui.
表哥
You're back already?
你怎么回来这么早啊
Look there!
看那里
So you knew everything.
所以你早就知道了
Your acting sucks,
你的演技实在是太差了
I saw through it
被我一眼就看穿
in one glance.
就一眼
I'm gonna tell granny
我要告诉外婆
you tricked and bullied me.
你骗我 欺负我
Nope,
不好使啊
not buying it.
我现在已经不吃你这套
Hold it in.
给我憋回去
Spill it,
如实招来啊
why do you want my passport?
你拿我护照干什么
You're not getting
你这么对我
anything out of me after that.
我才不会告诉你
You sure?
你确定
Help, help, help!
救命啊 救命啊 救命啊
0.01 mm shorter.
短了零点零一毫米
Let go of my lipstick!
你 你放开我的小权杖
I'm gonna get you for this!
我跟你拼了
0.01, 0.01...
零点零一 零点零一
Oh, 1.0 mm's gone.
一点零没了
I'll never
我是不会
submit to darkness.
向黑暗势力低头的
Fine.
行
Spill it, or not?
说还是不说
Good.
好
I give up.
我败了
Please tell me
我求求你告诉我
the truth.
你到底要干吗
I'll buy you anything
我可以给你买任何东西
you want.
你想要买的
Skins for games, clothes,
不管是游戏皮肤 衣服
skincare, luxury items.
还是说保养品 奢侈品
You name it!
护肤品
Tell me the truth!
你告诉我吧
Okay. Wait and see.
好 你给我等着
Don't push me
你别逼我使出
to my last resort.
最后的大绝招
I don't have a weak spot.
我苏小妹就没有弱点
Everyone,
各位观众
let's see some magic happen.
带你们来见证一下奇迹
Enough?
好了
Out!
给我出去
Get out!
你给我出去
Alright, alright.
我走 我走
What?
干什么
That's enough.
差不多得了啊
It won't bother you.
你做你的 我拍我的
I gotta pee.
我要上厕所了
Get out before I count to three.
我数三个数给我出去
One, two, three!
三 二 一
I gotta pee, you hear it?
上厕所听到没